前情提要
幕雨字幕組譯制
翻譯：Brynt&超威閆叔  校訂：Brynt&超威閆叔
時間軸：花格子神尼&拜仁小攀  后期&特效：Brynt
嘿
Hey.
Hey you.
有事兒嗎
What's up?
你是來借天文學筆記之類的嗎
You need my astronomy notes or something?
不
No
我貌似有點醉了
I might be a little drunk.
- 是嗎  - 只有一點點啦
- Yeah? - Like a little.
我明白了
I'm getting that, actually.
嗯  這樣就說得通了
Yeah, that makes sense.
你需要地方休息嗎
Do you need somewhere to crash?
你室友在嗎
Is your roommate here?
不  他不在
No, he is not.
你頭發臟透了
Your hair is all messed up.
嗯  我并不期望你能...
Yeah, I wasn't expecting you to...
事實上
Actually...
你喝醉了
You've been drinking, you know.
你可能不知道自己在干嘛
You might not know what you're doing.
我不想...
I don't want...
嘿  嘿
Hey, hey.
把我的元音打開
Turn my vocal up.
算了
Forget it.
還是弄回原樣吧
Just put it back where it was.
天吶
Oh, boy.
停  停
Stop. Stop.
沒感覺
Not feeling it.
沒找到感覺
你到底是沒感覺到什么
What exactly aren't you feeling?
要是我知道的話
Well, if I knew that,
我不就感覺到了嗎
then I'd be feeling it, wouldn't I?
我不想跟你爭那個
I cannot argue that point.
你想先休息十分鐘嗎
Do you want to, maybe, take ten,
十分鐘再戰
and recharge your batteries,
休息過后我們來再試一次
and we'll come and try it again?
不  我不需要重新再來  老兄
No,I don't need to recharge my batteries,bro.
當前可不是我奧利弗·羅馬的錯
This is not Oliver Rome's fault right now.
現在聽起來感覺跟我們昨天走之前不一樣
It sounds different than when we left it last night.
聽起來完全不同
It sounds way different.
好吧  你想進來聽聽回放嗎
OK.Do you want to come in,and hear the playback?
我敢打賭你會改變曲調的
Because I bet you'll change your tune.
再試一次也不會有所不同
It's not going to sound any different.
因為現在聽起來
Because this sounds like you
像是你在這兒上面躺了一夜
slept on the board last night,
- 所有聲音聽起來都不對勁  - 是嗎  我才是那個
- and everything sounds different. -Oh, I'm the one
處在半睡眠狀態的人好嗎
that's half asleep.
對  對  對
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
你別以為你是那個按鍵子的家伙就...
You think just 'cause you're pushing buttons...
我覺得你們廠的所有調子都爛得要死
I think all the tones sounds like crap.
這都是你一個人的錯
Whose fault could this be,other than yours?
挺有趣的  對吧
Fun, right?
我希望你今晚上沒打算睡覺
I hope you weren't planning on sleep tonight.
你他娘的現在是認真的嗎
Are you freaking serious right now?
哦吼  羅馬把他那豬肉餅帽摘掉了  這可不妙啊
Oh,Rome lost the porkpie.That's not a good sign.
你料到了嗎  看到了嗎  看到了嗎
You know this? You see this? You see this?
- 你明知道我現在日子很難熬 - 這一切都是真的
- You know I'm having a hard time.
- This is happening right now.
“克羅斯比  我覺得我的歌糟透了”
"Crosby, I'm afraid my songs suck.
“我那脆弱的自尊心承受不了了”
And my fragile ego, it can't handle that."
“我很煩躁 因為我家還有個煩人的嬰兒”
"And I'm upset because I have a demonic baby at home
“而且我已經一周都沒合過眼了”
and I haven't slept for seven days."
“我得躺會兒  我的生活是怎么回事兒”
"I need to get laid, man.What's going on with my life?"
天吶  事情好像真鬧言重了誒
Oh, my God. It's getting serious.
我得進去勸個架了
I should get in there.
對  好吧
Yeah, all right.
祝你好運
Well, good luck.
謝你吉言
Thanks.
管你呢  現在這兒可是我的地盤
Whatever, this is my studio right now!
啊~
Ah.
嘿  我是你那惡貫滿盈的小伙伴
Hey, it's your partner in crime.
猜猜誰剛才跟你遭遇了同樣的境遇
So guess who just bested you
接到了一條超簡潔的回絕信
for the shortest rejection email yet?
“經過多方查實  所有職位都已滿員”
"Per your inquiry,the position has been filled."
你感覺到能再愛了對吧
Yeah,you can feel the love there,can't you?
這就讓我想到了你
Anyway, it made me think of you.
于是就覺得該打給你
So just thought I'd call.
好嗎
Okay?
好吧
Okay.
拜
Bye.
嘿  我是你那惡貫滿盈的小伙伴
Hey, it's your partner in crime.
猜猜誰剛才跟你遭遇了同樣的境遇
So guess who just bested you
接到了一條超簡潔的回絕信
for the shortest rejection email yet?
嘿
Hey.
你來這兒有事嗎
What are you doing here?
沒出什么事吧
Is everything okay?
當然  當然
Yeah, yeah.
剛才我在家  然后想到你卻在這兒
I just,I don't know,I was at home, and you were here,
我就感覺我們倆的心沒有在一起
and I was feeling like we weren't connecting.
- 嗯  - 就這樣
- Yeah. - Yeah.
嗯
Yeah.
我知道工作到很晚并不甚完美  但是...
I know working late is not ideal,but, you know,
我得把這些文件處理完才能出這門
until I get out from under this pile,
我得繼續做下去  所以...
I got to keep up with it, so...
我們是能談談這些事兒
it's something we can talk about,
但我別無選擇
but there's no other way for me.
我只能全部完工才能出去
To get out from under all of this mess.
我來這不是為了談談
I didn't come here to talk.
很明顯  你不是
No, you didn't.
這還真是頭一遭呢
Uh, wow. This is a first.
要是你沒時間的話...
I mean, if you don't have time...
- 怎么會呢  我有的是時間呢  - 好吧
- No, no, I have the time. - Okay.
好吧  我得先確保...
Okay, let me just be sure that's...
嗷
ooh, ow.
對不起  我先把...
I'm sorry,I just...
不不不  沒關系  并無大礙
no, no, it's fine,it's fine, it's fine.
- 好吧  - 嗯
- Yeah. - Yeah.
為人父母
♪ May God bless and keep you always ♪
♪ And may your wishes all come true ♪
♪ May you always do for others ♪
♪ And let others do for you ♪
♪ may you build a ladder to the stars ♪
♪ And climb on every rung ♪
♪ and may you stay ♪
♪ forever young ♪
♪ may you grow up to be righteous ♪
♪ May you grow up to be true ♪
♪ May you always know the truth ♪
♪ And see the lights surrounding you ♪
♪ May you always be courageous ♪
♪ Stand upright and be strong ♪
♪ And may you stay ♪
♪ forever young ♪
♪ may you stay ♪
第五季第七集
- 早上好  - 嗯
- Good morning. - Mm.
嗯  昨晚真是愉快啊
So, um, that was fun last night.
天吶  我現在頭還昏昏沉沉的
God, I'm so hung over.
你還好嗎
Are you all right?
你在等著用這間嗎
Are you waiting for one of these?
- 沒有  你可以先進去  - 太好了  謝謝
- No, you can go ahead. - Great, thank you.
好吧  祝你愉快
Okay, well, have a good day, I guess.
嗯
Mm.
我幫你把藥都備好了  這樣就...
And I picked up your prescriptions, so...
我怎么會需要兩盒
Well, how come I need two boxes?
難道是我病情加重了嗎
What, am I getting worse?
沒有  我只是另外多揀了一份而已
No, I just picked up another one.
這樣你就不必費神再去填滿它了
So you wouldn't have to think about refilling them.
那謝謝了
Oh. Thanks.
過來  坐一會兒
Here, sit down for a minute.
好吧
Okay.
- 這是美證券交易所  - 嗯
- This is Amex. - Yeah.
我給你做了份小抄
And I made a cheat sheet for you.
你可能會用到的所有號碼
All the numbers you could possibly need.
我要待的酒店
The hotel, of course,where I'll be staying.
藝術學校
The art school.
- 還有布朗斯基家的電話  - 誰
- The Brunsky's. - Who?
布朗斯基
The Brunsky's.
- 布朗斯基  - 我們鄰居
- Brunsky's?  - Our neighbors.
就挨著的那家
Next door.
哦~
Oh, huh.
這個很好
This is very nice.
所有的號碼全在上面
All the numbers are here.
所有你可能會用得到的東西
Everything you could possibly need,
除了你早就該爛熟于心的
except for the alarm code,
報警碼  你記得對吧
which you have in your head, right?
給個提示
Give me a hint.
我們的結婚紀念日
Our anniversary.
哦~
Oh.
你都準備好了嗎
So, you're all set, you know.
謝謝  親愛的
Thanks, honey.
我準備就緒了
I'm all set.
因為你得獨自一人待在家一段時間
'Cause you're gonna be here all by yourself.
嗯  我不會有事兒的
Yeah, I'll be fine.
好嗎
Okay?
好了 好了 “瘋子麥克斯”
All right. All right, "mad Max."
拍得不錯
This is good.
接下來試試
Let's try the 100 macro.
100Micro物鏡鏡頭
With the lens hood now.
100 macro with lens hood.
這兒怎么會有一張薩拉姑姑的照片
Why is there a picture of aunt Sarah in here?
你怎么跑那兒去了  麥克斯
Why are you in there, Max?
拜托  你得離我的東西遠點兒
Come on,huh.You gotta stay out of my stuff.
是你讓我過來拿100Micro物鏡鏡頭的
You told me to get a lens hood.
對  是我叫你做的
Yeah, I did.
物鏡在這兒呢
Lens hood.
好了  走吧  我們快拍完了
Come on, let's go. We're almost done.
我看了部描寫連環殺手的電影
I saw a movie about a serial killer.
他也喜歡把照片藏起來
He kept hidden pictures too.
這些才不是藏起來的呢
They're not hidden.
他喜歡把照片藏床底下
Only he hid them under his bed.
好了 麥克斯 我沒有把照片藏起來 只是放在抽屜里而已
Okay,they weren't hidden,Max.They're in a drawer.
連環殺手有91%的都是男性  而且54%是白人
Serial killers are 91% male,54 white.
他們的平均智商為113
Their average I.Q. Is 113,
高于人類平均智商水平
which is considered above average intelligence.
你是個白人  還是男性  而且非常聰明
You're white and male and smart,
所以你可能是個連環殺手
so you could be a serial killer.
我不是什么連環殺手  麥克斯
I'm not a serial killer, Max.
- 好吧  - 好吧
- Okay. - Okay.
你得停止做那些統計之類的東西
You gotta stop with all the stats and everything.
這些基本上都來自網絡上
That's from the Internet.
你上網太過于頻繁了
You're on the Internet way too much.
維基百科在很長一段時間內是不會消失的
That Wikipedia, it's...unplug once in a while.
所以你得多去外面走走  而且你太蒼白了
You should go outside. You're pale, too.
多出去曬點太陽
Get some sun.
你還愛著她嗎
Do you still like her?
沒有
No.
我像一個朋友那樣愛著她
No, I like her as a friend.
要是你不愛她了
If you don't like her,
那你為什么不把她的照片丟掉
then why don't you throw the picture away?
因為這是張好照片
Because it's a good picture.
或許我只是想保存下來而已
And maybe I just want to keep it.
- 肯定是因為你還愛著她  - 我沒有  麥克斯
- Because you like her. - No, Max!
你現在聲音高了八度
Well, now you're raising your voice.
這就意味著你生氣了或是感到失意了
Which means you're angry or frustrated.
我沒有生氣  我或確實許很失意
I'm not angry. I'm frustrated, maybe, yeah.
聽著  麥克斯 你薩拉姑姑跟我之間
Look, Max, your aunt Sarah and I,
對 我們曾經是相愛過
yeah, we did like each other once,
但后來我們不再相愛了  以后也不會再愛了
and then we stopped,and that's what happens.
這就是成年人的世界  很麻煩也很奇怪
It's adult stuff,and it's messy,and it's weird.
我們倆不是同一類人
We were different people.
我有怪癖  而她有古里古怪的
I'm cranky. She's flaky.
我們都有各自的包袱
We both had baggage.
我們沒能在一起  就是這樣
It didn't work out, that's the point.
- 包袱  - 對  包袱
- Baggage? - Yeah, baggage.
包袱
Baggage.
真是這玩意兒才讓一段感情
That's the stuff you bring into a relationship,
出現破裂
if you want to ruin it.
這根本說不通  包袱是用來旅行用的
That doesn't make any sense.Suitcases are for trips.
你說得對  非常對  確實是用來旅行的
That's right, exactly right. It's a trip.
是一場需要一個大包袱的長途旅行
It's a long trip with a big suitcase.
一場充滿痛苦的旅行
Filled with pain.
聽起來你是在隱喻
That sounds like a metaphor.
我不喜歡隱喻
I don't like metaphors.
好  那就別碰我的抽屜
All right, well, then stay out of my drawers.
那薩拉姑姑有你的照片嗎
Does aunt Sarah have pictures of you?
你快煩死我了
You're killing me.
好了  各位  過來吃飯啦
All right, guys, eat up. Come get your treat.
你最好了  謝謝
Man, you're good. Thanks.
我們剛才還在想午飯呢  然后它就奇跡般地出現了
We just think about lunch and, boom, it appears.
你說對了  我就是個食物魔法師
That's right, I'm a magician of food.
這里面沒放松果吧
No pine nuts in this?
我寧愿死都不會把松果
I would rather die than let there be
放進你的沙拉里
a pine nut in your salad.
要有的話我會殺了你的
I would kill you.
我今天早上還在洪堡親手一點一點
You know,I also hand picked the strawberries.
把里面的草莓給揀出來呢
in Humboldt this morning.
你是以此為生的  對嗎
You live for this, don't you?
對  我的生活就是關心你們的飲食習慣
Yes, your digestive habits are my life.
是嗎
Right?
我晚上睡覺的時候你們就好好想想吧
Think about it when I go to sleep at night.
每個樂隊都需要一個安博
You know, every band needs an Amber,
至少我是這么認為的
that's what I think.
- 對  雇我做全職吧  全職哦  - 得要倆安博
- Yeah,sign me up full time.Full time.- Two Ambers.
要倆  還得是全職的
Two of 'em. Yeah. All the time.
對
Yeah.
對  看看這個家伙
Yeah.Look at this guy.
- 很明顯你們需要的  - 你有搞笑機嗎
- Yeah,you need to,obviously.- You have a funny machine?
事實上  我們可以用個搞笑機來代替
We could use a funny machine.
- 那樣就好了  - 那樣就真是再好不過了
- That would be nice. - That'd be real nice.
嗨  親愛的
Hi, honey.
嘿 藍博
Hey, Rambo.
奧利弗
Oliver...
你有空嗎  我們能談談嗎
You got a second? Can we talk?
- 給各位  我們倆能出去談談么  - 平靜的進來
- You guys,can we talk? - Come in peace.
- 行  - 自由萬歲
- Yeah. - Freedom.
讓我先緩口氣
Give it a break.
嗨  抱歉
Hi, sorry.
他最壞了
He's the worst.
我跟富蘭克林談過了
So, I just talked to Franklin,
他答應我了
and he's gonna do it.
他說只要我們想做  他誰是都可以從洛杉磯飛過來
He said he'd come up from L.A. any time we want to,
他會做我們在市政廳結婚的見證人
and he'll be our witness at city hall.
哦  哦
Oh, oh.
天吶  真是太好了  我太高興了
God, that's so nice. I'm so glad.
- 可是  - 可是什么
- But... - But?
我媽啊
My mom.
我跟她談過之后  我覺得她現在會
After talking to my mom,I just feel like she's going.
想去參加婚禮
to want to be a part of it now.
那是段很好的談話  而且我覺得...
It was a really good conversation, and I feel like...
- 那太好了  我很高興你媽能  - 嗯
- Oh,that's great,I'm glad that  - Yeah.
跟我們站在同一條線上
your mom's on board.
這真是至關重要啊
That's really important.
但是...但是這樣的話
But, but so,
我考慮要辦一場真正的婚禮
I was thinking maybe we could have a real ceremony.
現在一切都是站在我們這邊的
Now that things are,like, on board, you know?
當然
Yeah.
這樣好嗎  我是說  我不知道
Is that okay? I mean, I don't know.
要是我們能拍張婚紗照不是很甜蜜嗎 要是我們想...
Wouldn't it be sweet if we had pictures,or if we wanted
我可以解決好的
I mean, I figured all that stuff out.
你不生氣嗎
Are you mad?
我很抱歉總是搖擺不定  可是...
I'm sorry I'm, like,switching a lot, but...
不不不  你想怎么做都行  好嗎
No, no, hey. Hey. Whatever you want to do,okay?
那你想要怎么做
So what do you want to do?
嗯...
Oh, um...
- 我們得制定個計劃  - 嗯 我現在沒注意
- I mean, let's make a plan. - Yeah, I don't know.
我們都該坐下來然后...
We should both sit down and...
嘿  小貓  我需要你把海鹽挑出來
hey, kitten, I need a little sea salt action.
我得去處理這些事兒了  我很抱歉
I have to go deal with this. I'm so sorry.
- 好吧  - 你的草莓掉出來了
- Okay. - Your strawberries are out.
我們還有事兒要討論呢
We have things we need to talk about.
等我回家再討論好嗎  我們得走了
Let's talk about it when I get home,and we'll get going.
- 好吧  - 好嗎
- Okay. - Okay.
- 愛你 愛你喲  拜  - 我也愛你
- Love you, love you, bye. - I love you too.
- 天吶  我來幫你把海鹽挑出來  - 快點兒
- God, let me dig up some sea salt. - Come on.
你都不那樣吻我
You don't kiss me like that.
嗯 那個...
Yeah, well...
媽  這個土豆泥實在是太好吃了
Mom, the mashed potatoes are killer.
- 好吃到爆了  - 麥克斯
- They're so good. - Max.
麥克斯  把照相機放下來  我們要吃飯呢
Max, put the camera away. We're eating here.
茱莉亞  喬呢
Julia, where's Joel?
喬本來打算來的
Joel is... he wanted to be here.
但是他又得加班
But he's working late again.
又加班
Again?
那個“槍手皮特”對他如何
How's "pistol Pete" treating him?
皮特讓他總是加班
Pete is working him late nights.
- 她真是個嚴苛的上司   - 她讓他隨時準備待命
- She's a slave driver.- She's keeping him on his toes.
挺好的  這是個不錯的機會
It's good.That's an amazing opportunity.
這對他  對我們全家來說
It's amazing for him.
- 都不是件壞事兒  - 哦  對對對
- For us, you know. - Oh, yeah, yeah.
天吶  我還在嚼東西呢
Oh, my God. I'm chewing.
好了  麥克斯  別再拍你薩拉姑姑了  麥克斯
All right,Max.No more pictures of aunt Sarah,Max.
漢克給薩拉姑姑拍了很大一張照片
Hank has a huge picture of aunt Sarah.
就放在他的抽屜里
That he keeps in his drawer.
- 好吧  - 什么
- Okay. - What?
什么  你說什么
What?What... what'd you say?
她打扮得多...
How dressed is she in this...
那是因為他曾愛過你
It's because he liked you,
但是他說他現在不愛你了
but he says he doesn't like you anymore.
因為你古里古怪的  還有一大堆包袱
Because you're flaky, and you have baggage.
小鬼  這件事并不適合在餐桌上來討論
Buddy,that is not appropriate talk at the dinner table.
- 麥克斯  這是人家的私事   - 漢克親口說我有包袱的嗎
- Max,that's personal. - Hank told you I have baggage?
不好意思  我有包袱嗎
Excuse me. I have baggage?
這種情節里誰還會有包袱
Who has baggage in that scenario?
他還說你不能跟一個滿是包袱的家伙結婚
And he says that you shouldn't marry someone
因為他們生活在痛苦之中
who has baggage because they're filled with pain.
- 真是不好意思  - 麥克斯  別說了
- I'm so sorry. - Max, that's all.
別說了
We're done.
我先搞清楚  我們現在是在談論這個話題嗎
First of all,are we having this conversation?
這個話題不錯啊
This is the greatest conversation.
我們都討論過幾個月了
We've had in months.
非常抱歉我家小寶貝兒想聽這個了
I'm sorry that the baby's missing it.
我為什么要講這些呢
Why am I talking?
而且漢克跟我倆也是最好的朋友
Also, Hank and I are best friends too.
你們倆是最好的朋友
You're best friends?
對  我放學之后跟他呆的時間
Yeah,I spend more time with him after school,
比學校任何一個人都要長
than any one person in school,and I'm his only friend,
這就說明我們是最好的朋友
which makes us best friends.
寶貝  我敢肯定漢克還有其他的朋友
Honey, I'm sure Hank has other friends.
事實上  他沒有其他朋友
Actually, he doesn't.
他還給我取了個奇怪的外號“瘋子麥克斯”
He also calls me a weird nickname called "mad Max."
他甚至在我都沒生氣的時候叫我這個名字
He even calls me "mad Max" when I'm not angry,
- 這就非常奇怪了  - 這才不是個奇怪的外號呢
- which is really weird. - That's not a weird nickname.
- 這是個很酷的外號  - 那個外號很不錯 麥克斯
- That's a cool nickname. - That's a great nickname,Max.
說到包袱的問題
Well, speaking of baggage,
我要宣布一件事兒
I have a little announcement to make.
- 是嗎  - 是的
- Oh? - Yes.
我的藝術班要去旅行
My art class is taking a trip.
- 不錯嘛  - 我們要去意大利
- Oh, cool. - We're going to Italy.
- 什么  - 那真是太棒了
- What? - That's great.
- 哇哦  - 那太棒了  卡米爾
- Wow. - That's great, Camille.
更像是去開一個研討會
Well, it's like a retreat. A workshop.
- 去多久  - 一個月
- How long? - A month.
老爸  這可是你夢寐以求的旅行啊
Dad, this is like your dream vacation.
當老媽一整天都在工作的時候
In your speedo, on the mediterranean,
在地中海悠閑地散步  吃著意面
eating pasta while mom works all day,
還灑在你的胸前
spill some on your chest...
- 實際上  你們老爸不去  - 什么
- actually, dad's not going. - What?
你們爸不去
Dad's not going.
你不去嗎
You're not going?
爸  怎么回事
Dad, what's the deal?
就你一個人去嗎
It's just you?
就我一個人
Just me.
你為什么不去  老爹
Why aren't you going, pop?
你能把那個土豆泥遞給我嗎
Would you pass the mashed potatoes, please?
對
Yep.
謝謝
Thank you.
花椰菜做得蠻不錯的
This broccoli dish is really good.
嗯
Yes.
嗨
Hi.
你穿這身是干嘛去   同學會嗎
What's this for you? In the classmate's?
- 什么  - 你又需要什么
- What? - What do you need now?
我不是來借東西的
I'm not here to borrow anything.
我得開始向你收費了
I should start charging you for this.
不  我只是來拜訪你一下而已
No, I just came to visit.
- 真的嗎  - 是的
- Really? - Yeah.
好吧  你最近還好吧
All right, well, how are you?
很好
I'm good.
你呢
How are you?
就跟平常一樣
As usual, you know.
嗯
Yeah.
嗯~
Um.
聽著  我...
Listen,I...
我...
I...
我要說什么來著
What am I trying to say?
我們倆結束了真的很令人難過
Its sad sometimes that it's over between us.
對
Yeah.
但這都過去了
But it's over.
我知道
I know that.
我知道你知道
I know, I know.
- 我們討論過那個的  - 對
- We discussed that. - Right.
我們才討論了不久
We discussed that a while ago.
只是...
It's just that, you know,
麥克斯能到這來對他來說真的很好
Max being here has been so great for him,
而且他還把你當做他最好的朋友
and he feels like you're his best friend.
他跟我說了很多事兒
But then he said a bunch of stuff.
就在昨天晚上吃飯的時候跟我們說的
At the dinner table about us.
你能告訴他這些
That was so surprisingly intimate,
還真是有點親密無間呢
for you to have talked to him,
所以我來這兒只是想讓你知道
and so I just wanted to make sure that you,
你不能再跟他說我的事兒
you know,that you can't be talking to him about me.
先聲明  是他跟我談起你的  好嗎
First of all, he was talking to me,okay?
我很抱歉你被討論了
I'm sorry that you came up.
不是我被討論不討論的問題
It wasn't that I came up.
只是討論的內容實在是...
It was the content of...
我不知道你想讓我說什么
I don't know what you want me to say.
孩子總是好奇  愛問這問那的  僅此而已
It's like 20 questions with this kid,that's all.
但是你是成年人
But, you're the adult.
你不必什么問題都回答他
You don't have to give him 20 answers.
我就說了那么點事兒
That's all I'm saying.
并不是我為你寫了首情歌
It's not like I'm sitting writing you love songs,
然后唱給他聽  好嗎
and singing it to him, okay?
我知道
I know.
我并不是說你做了那樣的事兒
I'm not saying that you are doing anything like that.
是麥克斯跑過來找我的 好嗎
You know, he came to me, Max,
我只是覺得我做的事兒是對那孩子好而已
and I thought I was doing something good for this kid...
你確實為他做了些好事兒
You are doing something good.
我不喜歡這樣子
I don't like this, you know.
這真是...他...像...他...我還有事要忙
This is...he...look...he...I got a business to run,
或許他根本就不該來這兒
and maybe he just shouldn't be here,
因為他確實有點兒煩人
because he is a little grating.
不  我沒想這么說
No, don't, that's not what I'm saying.
我沒說他不該來這兒
I'm not saying he shouldn't be here.
好好好  是我說的好嗎
Well, I am. I am saying that, okay?
我得在這兒工作
I got to do things around here,
我不想有個小孩在我周圍轉悠  好嗎
and I shouldn't have a kid walking around here,okay?
這是在做生意  我在做生意
This is a business. It's a business.
- 別這樣  - 我現在有事兒要忙
- Don't do this. - I got a job to do right now.
我現在得拍照了
I gotta do a shoot right now.
好吧
Okay.
我是說  這個聽起來...
I mean, it just... it sounds...
聽起來是奧利弗自己毫無生氣
that sounds like Oliver Rome is boring Oliver Rome.
對  雖然我覺得有點不科學
Yeah, which I did not think was possible.
但是這真就是為什么七十年代的唱片公司會給藝人嗑藥了
This is exactly why labels gave artists drugs in the '70s.
我完全不知道該拿他怎么辦了
I have no idea what to do for him.
你們有見過他們現場演出過嗎
Have you guys ever seen them live?
- 啊  沒有  - 嗯
- Uh, no. - Mm-mm.
好吧  我之前在紅惡魔劇場見到過他們的表演
Okay,I saw them a couple of times at the red devil,
他們表演得真的很好
and it was actually very good.
奧利弗那時候精力十足
Oliver had, like, a lot of energy,
而且魅力十足
and he was really charismatic and stuff.
真的嗎
Really?
很明顯在這兒沒有發現
Well, apparently he doesn't find the luncheonette
像在紅惡魔那一樣有助于創造力發展的激情
as conducive to creativity as the red devil.
- 沒有  我不知道該怎么辦了  - 不  我覺得...
- No.I don't know how to fix that. - No.I was...
我覺得吧
Well I was thinking, actually,
你知道他需要什么
I mean, you know how he needs, like,
比如說  隨時激發一下他的自尊心
his ego stroked all the time.
激發一下  對
Stroked, yeah.
他需要四只手來給他按摩
He needs, like a four hand massage.
還得打上精油  放著恩雅的曲子
With exotic oils and Enya playing.
對  那為什么我們不直接給他...
Right,so why don't we just give him that,and you know,
給他找一堆觀眾來這兒看他表演
give him like an audience to perform to here.
你是說在這個工作室
What do you mean,right here in the studio?
對  差不多
Yeah, pretty much.
那我們得找多少人過來
Well, how many people are we talking about?
我不知道  盡量把這兒塞滿吧
I don't know, as many as we could squeeze in.
我們讓她們打扮得又年輕又惹火
We'll make them young and hot,and young and hot...
熱火從來都不是件壞事兒
Well, hot's never a bad thing.
我不懂  安博
I don't know, Amber.
他們自己錄音就已經讓自己
It's tough enough to get these five guys to focus.
夠難集中精力了
When it's just them.
我不敢想象給他們弄一個派對會怎樣
I don't know about throwing them a party.
不不不  不是開派對  更像是個小型音樂會
No, no, not a party, but,like, an actual concert.
說真的  就弄個特殊的事件
Seriously, like, have it just be a specific event.
來記錄下這些歌
To record the song,you know what I mean?
可能會管用
It could work.
就跟黑鴉樂隊在“冰霜之前”
I mean that's what the black crowes did
那張專輯上做的那樣  那真是張好專輯
on "before the frost", and that's a damn good album.
- 真是太棒了  那張專輯  - 我也不清楚
- It's a great album. - And I don't know,
這件事就交給我來處理
I'll organize it and stuff.
我把他們的網站都建好了
I mean,I have their website finished and everything.
你建好了網站
You finished the website?
- 就這個  對   - 你做的嗎
- Here. Yeah. - You made this?
當然  扎克有幫過忙啦
Yeah, I mean Zack helped,
但這些是他們想要的
but, I mean, this is what they wanted.
看起來很棒嘛
That looks great.
所有事兒都交給我來辦
I mean,I'll organize the whole thing,you know.
社會媒體還有宣傳之類的事兒都交給我來辦
I'll do social media stuff,and get the word out there,
去找人還有吃喝的東西我都包了
and find people, and I'll get drinks and stuff,
前提是你們喜歡這個主意
I mean, if you like the idea.
你覺得呢
What do you think?
為什么不呢  我就指著這個了呢
Why not? I'm up for it.
好吧  那你就去辦吧
All right, let's go for it.
- 真的  - 當然 去做吧
- Yeah? - Let's do it.
- 真的嗎  - 真的
- Yeah? - Yeah.
太棒了
Great.
我們或許可以把老爸和老媽叫到這兒來解決好這件事兒
Maybe we could bring mom and dad here and sort this out.
我不知道行不行得通  但我真搞不懂
I don't know, but I don't understand.
為什么他們要分開旅行
Why they're taking separate vacations at all.
他們之前有這樣子過嗎
Have they ever done that before?
沒有  他們之間肯定有什么事兒
No, something must have happened.
他們肯定吵架了
They're clearly in a fight.
你認為他們吵架了嗎
You think they're having a fight?
那肯定是因為去意大利不是老爸
It's probably just because it wasn't dad's idea.
- 提出的主意  “我生你的氣了
- to go to Italy. - "I'm mad at you.
我要去意大利”嗎
I'm going to Italy"?
意大利超出了老爸的安全區
Italy's outside of dad's comfort zone.
聽著  肯定是這樣子的
Listen, here's exactly what's happening.
他現在生氣了可能是因為他建議過
He's pouting right now because he probably suggested,
比如說  去美國某地的棒球場旅游
like, going on some ballpark tour of America,
而老媽說“不行”  所以他就生氣了現在
and she said "no,"and now he's pouting.
對  他可是很頑固的
Yeah, well, he can be pretty stubborn.
可是誰會對意大利生氣呢
Yeah, but who pouts about Italy?
- 去就行了啊  - 老爸嘛
- Just go. - Dad.
我覺得可能是因為時機不對
I just think the timing sucks 'cause, you know,
她為什么會現在去
why is she going now when.
她現在可是有一個小孫女出生呢
There's a grand baby on the ground?
她都不去看看她
She's not even going to be here?
好消息是  老爸也可以照顧小孫女
The good news is dad can baby...sit.
對  那還真是沒錯誒
Oh, yeah. That's a great idea.
- 他一個人嗎   - 那購物怎么辦
- Without mom? - What about shopping?
老爸甚至都不知道雜貨店在哪兒
Dad doesn't even know how the grocery store works.
對啊  我們不得不坐下來...
Yeah, we're going to have to sit down...
我們得制定一個表格
We're gonna have to make a grid.
我沒時間去管老爸
I don't have time for dad's schedule.
我不想去每天都去檢查他
I don't want to go checking on him.
- 不行  跟他在一起簡直如坐針氈  - 不  我沒時間
- No, he's a pain in the ass. - No, I don't have time.
我是個自由職業攝影師
I'm a free-lance photographer.
永遠都不知道什么時候會有人讓你給他的狗拍照
You never know when the dogs are going to call.
為什么一直都在說老爸
Why is this all about dad?
那老媽呢
What about mom?
那老媽呢  她可是在用自己的
What about mom, who's taken care
一生來照顧你們所有人呢
of everyone else her whole life?
而且我告訴你們  老爸根本就不聽老媽的意見
And,let me tell you,dad doesn't listen to her.
當老媽告訴他他需要什么的時候
When she tells him what she needs,
他根本理都不理
he doesn't listen to her.
所以她才想為自己做一些事兒
And so she's doing something for herself
這也可能是她第一次為自己考慮
for the first time probably in, you know,
不管他們在一起有多久了
however long they've been together.
所以她才想去意大利
So she's going to Italy.
老爸接受得了  你們也可以
Dad can damn well deal with it, and so can you.
我去拿點糖
I'm getting sugar.
- 嘿  - 嘿 有事嗎
- Hey, nats. - Oh, hey, what's up?
沒事  我就是路過而已
Nothing, I was just walking,
我姐姐在做一件事兒
and my sister, actually,is doing this thing.
就是在速食餐廳  一個錄音棚...
At the luncheonette,the recording studio...
對  我想起來了
Yeah, yeah.
他們現在
Well, they're doing this thing.
在錄音棚  好像是要一演唱會的形式
Where they're recording a band,
給一個樂隊錄音
like, a live performance in front of people.
提拔扶起來挺不錯的嘛  什么樂隊啊
That sounds cool. What band?
叫做“羅馬之燼”
They're called ashes of Rome.
嗯 好像沒聽過誒
Yeah, I don't know them.
但你聽了的話肯定會喜歡的
You'd probably like it, though.
我想說我們可以在那兒見面什么的
I was just going to say we could meet there or something,
- 當然前提是你想去的話  - 當然想去  聽起來挺酷的
- if you wanted to. - Yeah, that sounds cool.
我上課快遲到了
I'm actually going to be late for class,
所以你待會兒發短信告訴我細節吧
so just, like, text me the deets.
我們到時再商量一下  好了 待會見
We'll figure it out later.All right, see you.
好吧  待會兒見
Well, later.
哦~ 哦~
Oh, oh.
維克多  過來一下
Victor, come here, please.
西德妮  我告訴過你把你的手工作業收起來
Sydney, I told you to put your craft stuff away.
馬上就來  我們現在正忙著呢
In a minute. We're doing something.
馬上  給我過來
Now! Get over here!
我都跟你說過三次要把這些玩意兒收好
I told you three times to put this away!
維克多  你把這個玩意兒扔在樓梯上
Victor, this was on the stairs.
差點摔死我
I nearly died.
太沒有規矩了
This is out of control.
你們給我去樓上
You guys need to get upstairs,
把這些玩意兒干放哪兒放哪兒去
and put this stuff away where it belongs.
只要...
Just...
好嗎
All right?
嘿
Hey.
- 喬  - 稍等一會兒
- Joel. - Hang on one second.
你想讓之前那個家伙下來
Do you want the early guys off,
還是說我們加班再弄
or are we looking at overtime?
不用了  都做好了
No, no they're done.
不用加班了嗎
No overtime?
不用了  謝謝
No. Thanks.
這是個獎勵電話嗎
Hey, is this a Booty call?
不  不是
No. This is... no, it's not.
我很抱歉
I'm sorry.
- 怎么啦  - 我...
- What is it? - Just,I...
孩子們把房間弄得一團糟  我剛才失控了
The kids' mess,I just... I lost it.
我又失控了
I lost it in a whole new way.
我肯定還沒有那么糟  親愛的
I'm sure it wasn't that bad, honey.
相信我  我剛才因為他們做的事
Trust me, I'm giving them ammunition
對他們發火了
for any future therapy they might have.
太糟了
It was bad.
強硬一點
Just be firm, you know.
直到他們把房間整理好之前不準他們看電視  就這樣做
No screen time until their room's in order,that's it.
去過你想緩口氣的話  就把他們帶到你老爸家去
Or take them to your dad's if you need a break.
他很擅長對付小孩子
He's great with them.
不僅僅是孩子們的事  親愛的 是我
It's not just the kids, babe, it's me.
我...我有一點失控了
I'm... I'm losing it a little bit.
喬 我的工友們希望能加會兒班
Joel, my guys are supposed to get overtime.
- 你在干嘛呢  - 我知道 我知道 親愛的
- What are you doing? - I know, I know, Gabe.
先讓我...  你能給我點時間嗎
Just... let me just,can you give me one second?
就一會兒  老兄  抱歉
One second, buddy. Sorry.
親愛的  對不起
Hon, I'm sorry.
我知道你壓力很大  我也經歷過同樣的事兒
I know it's stressful, and I've been there.
你還好嗎
You okay?
嗯  我還好
Yeah, I'm fine.
- 你先去忙吧  - 好吧
- I'll let you go. - Okay.
愛你喲
Love you.
好吧
Okay.
小諾拉現在在他老爸哪兒呢
Little Nora's all situated for her daddy day.
謝謝你幫我提供方便
Thank you for helping facilitate that.
我覺得我在海瑟牽制住我之前
I think I have a couple of minutes
還有幾分鐘時間
before Heather gets a hold of me.
抱歉  我在整理資料呢
Sorry. I'm so out of it.
我...你想喝點什么嗎
I... do you want something to drink?
我都還沒...
I haven't even been...
不用了  我沒事  我都...
oh, no, I'm good. I'm coffee...
- 我都喝了兩杯咖啡了  - 你確定嗎
- I've had two cups. - Are you sure?
確定  你最近如何
Yeah. How are you?
做得怎么樣了
How are you doing?
- 我還好啦  - 是嗎
- I'm okay. - Yeah?
就是有點壓力大
I'm a little stressed.
我知道
I know.
計劃婚禮可是件大事
Planning a wedding is a big deal.
- 對啊  - 有一大堆事兒要做
- Yeah. - It's a lot of work.
我只是在
And you know, it's just that,
處理樂隊之類的事兒
on top of,like,dealing with the band stuff,
我們都不知道我們要怎么做
and we don't know what we want to do,
我不知道  我就是有點壓力而已
and I-I don't know...it's just been,it's like,stressful
太瘋狂了  壓力確實是很大
Crazy. It's very stressful.
這跟你很像嗎
Was it like this for you?
- 我是說 跟你的...  - 計劃嗎
- Does it,I mean,was it like... - Planning?
我都不知道這事兒呢
I don't even know anything about it.
他怎么跟你求婚的
How did he even propose?
你真想聽那個故事
You really want to hear that story?
- 當然  - 那是個很棒的故事
- Yeah. - I mean, it's a great story.
我很樂意給別人講
I love telling it.
天吶  就好像是大半輩子之前的事兒了
It's... gosh,I feel like it was,like,a lifetime ago.
我那時還很年輕  我們都還很年輕
I was so young. We were both so young.
他是在情人節第二天向我求的婚
He actually proposed to me the day after Valentine's day
誰會那樣做呢
Like, who does that?
但確實是很浪漫
But it was so sweet.
因為他知道我有多討厭情人節
Because he knew how much I hated Valentine's day.
我覺得那天的話太刻意而為之了
I think it's,like... I don't know, so manufactured,
還有點假  就好像是誰都能在那天這么做
and fake, and just,like, for everybody else.
所以他就決定在十五號那天向我求婚
So he decided to ask me to marry him on the 15th.
天吶  那真是太酷了
God, it was so cool.
我們倆當時都在上研究生
It was like, both in grad school.
我們當時才同居不到一個月
You know,we'd only been living together for about a month.
有一天早上我醒了之后
And we woke up early one morning,
天空灰蒙蒙的
and it was just this really gray,
窗外還飄著雨  是個很浪漫的早晨
and sort of rainy, romantic morning,
我們們就那樣躺在床上
and we were lying in bed,
都在聆聽著外面的細雨
the two of us, and listening to the rain,
他就突然伸出手來握住我的手
and he reached out, and grabbed my hand,
問我是否愿意跟他共度余生
and he asked me if I would spend the rest of my life with him.
真是非常簡單  也很純潔  平淡無奇
It was so simple,and just so pure,and,sounds corny,
但就是很美
but it was just beautiful,
也非常有意義
and it just made sense.
我敢肯定你也對瑞恩有同感
I mean, I'm sure you feel the same about Ryan,
這是我所珍視的東西
and it's something I'll always treasure.
它曾是我生命中...
It was the one thing in my life that...
意義非凡的一件事
that just made sense.
現在依然也是
It still does.
抱歉  是海瑟
Sorry. It's Heather.
我得走了
I got to go.
走吧  沒關系的
Go. Yeah.
好吧
Okay.
改日再見
I'll see you soon.
謝謝  真的很棒
Thanks. That was nice.
當然啦
Yeah, sure.
- 改日見  - 拜  寶貝
- See you soon. - Bye, babe.
好吧
Okay.
這是最適合飛行了
So this is top of the line.
保證能適應90%我們的房間的床
Guaranteed to fit into 90% of our bed compartments.
真的嗎  看起來真像是最佳航線專用包誒
Really?Well, it looks top of the line.
天吶  我當年到處旅行的時候
Oh, my gosh, when I was traveling so much
去幫別人打官司的時候  這箱子幫我大忙了呢
for all those depositions,it saved my life.
這是免燙隔間
This, the wrinkle-free compartment,
能裝很多衣服
holds so many clothes.
真的嗎
Really?
我去他們官網時上面是這么寫的
I went on their website and wrote a testimonial.
- 有那么好嗎  - 當然了
- It's that good? - Yeah.
謝謝  親愛的
Thank you, sweetie.
你考慮得太周到了  真是我的貼心小棉襖
So thoughtful of you.You're my thoughtful girl.
你確定我會用得到這個嗎
Are you sure you're not going to need this?
當然  我確定
Yes, I'm sure.
就相當于把房間搬到這個衣櫥里
It's just taking up room in the closet.
這就是專為你專為意大利而打造的
So this is... this is for you.This is for Italy.
- 嗯  - 我真為你驕傲
- Yeah. - I'm proud of you.
我為你做些事而感到驕傲
I'm proud of you for doing this.
- 我也是  - 對
- Me too. - Yeah.
我跟你老爸都待一起那么久了
You know, dad and I have been together so long.
我們幾乎都同穿一條褲子
We've been practically joined at the hip.
我有時候差點都忘了我們是兩個完全獨立的個體
I forget sometimes that we're two separate people.
他是個大男子主義者
You know, he's such a big personality, you know?
具有強烈的存在感
A huge presence in the room.
這一次不再是關乎他了  而是關乎我自己
This time it's not about him. It's about me.
關乎我的希求
About what I want.
關乎什么能讓我開心  以及去意大利的事
What makes me happy, and going to Italy,
是關乎我的事
it's about me.
是關乎這段婚姻中的另外一半
It's about the other person in the marriage.
怎么啦
What?
哦
Oh.
寶貝
Sweetie?
我只是為你感到高興而已  來擁抱一個
I'm just so happy for you. Come here.
哦~
Oh.
好了  進來吧  各位
All right, come on in, you guys.
喝的在這邊  自己找地方坐吧  好嗎
Drinks over there, and just find a spot to sit, okay?
給你
Here.
想要這個嗎
Here, you want these?
你想要的話也給你一個
Here you go, if you want them.
謝謝
Thanks.
抱歉  我需要這個
I need this. I'm sorry.
我給你們拿瓶新的
I'll get you new ones.
你好  最近如何
Hey, hi. How are you?
感謝你的到來
Thanks for coming.
- 你有看見奧利弗嗎  - 沒有  抱歉
- Have you seen Oliver? - No, sorry.
- 好吧  - 嗨
- Okay. - Hi.
最近怎么樣了  很高興見到你
How's it going? It's good to see you.
感謝你的到來  嗨  你還好嗎  很高興見到你們
Thanks for coming.Hi,how are you?It's good to see u.
感謝前來  各位
Thanks for coming, you guys.
玩得開心
Yeah, have a good time.
待會兒見
See you guys later.
好了  聽著  非常感謝你能來捧場
All right, listen, thanks for coming.
別玩了告訴你的朋友們來買這張唱片哦
Don't forget to tell all your friends to buy the album.
- 嘿  又看見奧利弗嗎  - 看見了
- Hey, have you seen Oliver? - Yes, I have.
他正躲在廁所呢
He's hiding out in the bathroom.
他說他得靜會兒  這樣才能集中精力
He said he needs to be alone so he can focus his energy,
之類的
or something like that.
那他是在吐嗎
Oh, so he's puking?Okay?
我覺得這是在吐的征兆
I think that's code for puking.
嘿  德魯  怎么啦
Hey, drew. What's going on?
你在找什么人嗎
You looking for somebody?
對  我等找娜塔莉
Yeah. I'm waiting for Natalie.
娜塔莉  就是喜歡喬妮·米歇爾的那個娜塔莉
Natalie "joni Mitchell" Natalie?
- 對  喜歡喬妮·米歇爾的那個娜塔莉  - 成事兒了
- Yeah,"joni Mitchell"Natalie. - Any luck with that?
當然了
Yeah, sure.
真的  是已經成事兒了  還是感覺快成事兒了
Really,like,have gotten lucky,or just feeling lucky?
別對你侄子的私事兒刨根問底
Stop trying to live vicariously through your nephew.
我都三個月沒出過門了  好嗎
I have a three-month-old at home.This is all I got.
我們約好在這兒見面的  所以還好啦
We're meeting here, so that's good.
- 那是在約會咯  - 聽起來不錯嘛
- So this is a date? - Sounds pretty good.
- 不是約會啦   - 聽起來就是嘛
- It's not a date, no. - Sounds like a date.
- 就是約會   - 我們更像是...
- It's a date. - We're kind of...
你們關系最終會平穩的
You might go steady eventually, too.
好像是在同居又有點不像
Together, but also not.
- 同居  - 有點啦
- Together? - Kind of.
有點  哇哦
Kind of? Wow.
你們現在已經發展到什么地步了
How deep are you into this situation?
我也搞不清楚
I can't tell, actually.
我在這大學生身上花的心血終于得到回報了
It seems my work on this college kid has paid off.
是哪個  紅頭發的那個嗎  到底是哪個
Which one, the redhead? Which one is it?
- 嘿  - 嘿
- Hey. - Hey.
嘿  你還好嗎
Hey, how's it going?
很好  很好
Good. Good.
好了
All right, yeah.
我們現在是非常想看到這些家伙的表演呢
We're so stoked to see these guys play.
你們想找個地方坐坐嗎
Do you guys want to get a seat?
所有人
Everyone?
- 你們想去這邊嗎  - 好吧 走吧
- You guys want to head down this way?- OK,let's go.
我這會兒估計就該跟
I would have probably gone
那個黑妞一塊走了  你懂我的
with the black girl, you know me.
這更像是我的了努力得到了回報
It looks like my work really paid off, though.
哈哈  他們在同居了誒
Ka-boom. They're together.
我有種不祥的預感
I don't have a good feeling about this.
天吶
Oh, my goodness.
- 怎么回事  - 好吧  好吧
- What's going on here? - Okay, okay.
- 天吶  - 他要調音了現在
- Oh, my God. - Now, he's gonna tune.
- 這真是...  - 這到底怎么回事兒
- This is, um... - Why is this happening?
太糟了  這真是我這一生中最糟糕的時刻了
This is horrible,this is the worst day of my life.
天吶  這個家伙...
Oh, my God.This guy...
♪那我們呢  那我們呢
♪So what about us? What about us?
♪那我們的環游愿望呢
?What about wanderlust?
♪那我們自由下落的愛戀呢
♪What about love in a freefall now?
♪那夜晚又如何呢
♪But what about nights?
事實上  他還不賴嘛
Actually, he's not bad.
♪那你這食言又算什么呢
♪What about this on the way back out?
♪我需要一絲笑聲  一絲笑聲
♪I need a little laugh need a little laugh
♪可能需要展露一絲笑顏  一絲笑顏
♪Might need a little laugh need a little laugh
很棒的救場  安博
Great save, Amber.
- 謝謝  - 干得不錯
- Thanks. - Good job.
♪就一絲  只需一絲
♪Just a little just a little
♪就那么一絲而已
♪Just a little that
♪我們又將去往何處  去往何處
♪so where do we go? Where do we go?
♪我甚至根本不知道
♪'Cause even I don't know
很感謝你邀請我來
Hey, thanks for that.
他們簡直是太棒了
That was, like,so cool to be right in there with them.
對啊  我也喜歡他們
Yeah, I like it too.
他們有一點流行搖滾風  但可能是最完美的結合了
They're kind of pop rocky,but in the best way possible.
嗯 我明白
Yeah, I can see it.
我的朋友們要在斐凱酒吧開派對
My friends want to hit this party at phi kap.
你想一起來嗎
You want to come with us?
不了  我得留下來
No, I should probably stay back, actually.
我得幫我姐才那些裝飾之類的  所以...
I have to help my sister tear down, so...
哦
Oh.
這不會是因為我們那晚的緣故吧
This isn't about the other night, is it?
- 不是  當然不是  - 不是嗎
- No, no. - No?
那晚真的很棒
Because, I mean, that was great.
- 嗯  - 而且我也喜歡你
- Yeah. - And I like you.
我只是希望你不要會錯意
I just hope I didn't give you the wrong idea.
不會
No.
那只是一夜情而已  對吧
I mean, that was a hook up, right?
就是一夜情而已  我們一夜情了
It was just a hook up.Yes, we hooked up.
- 確實是  - 我們現在是大學生了
- That happened, yeah. - We're in college, you know.
- 對  - 我很努力才進了這所大學
- Yeah. - I worked so hard to get here.
我高中成績很好的
I was so good in high school.
我現在只是想
Now, I kind of just want to.
- 休息放松一下  閑逛一下  多見見朋友  - 很好
-Kick back and relax,hang out,meet people.-It's all right.
絕對的  我完全明白
Totally. I fully understand that.
我希望你不想談戀愛
Yeah, I mean you wouldn't want a relationship, or...
不會   不會
No, no.
好吧  所以我們還是朋友
Okay, so, we're good?
- 當然  我們還是朋友   - 好吧
- Yeah, we're totally good. - Okay.
我們...嗯
We're... yeah.
你確定不想跟我們一起去
Are you sure you don't want to just,like,tag along?
嗯  我還是留下的好
Yeah, I should probably stay.
好吧
Okay.
- 改日見  - 好吧 拜
- I'll see you. - Yeah, bye.
各位  你們棒到爆了
You guys, you totally killed it!
太贊了
That was so awesome!
真的
Seriously.
史上最佳搖滾樂隊
Best rock band ever.
天吶  太好了
Oh, my God. That was so good.
太棒了
That was great.
沒有你們我不可能做到的
I couldn't have done it without you.
太謝謝你了
Thank you.
真是太開心了
That was so fun.
- 嗨  親愛的  - 嘿
- Hi, baby. - Hey.
玩得還好嗎
How you doing?
- 做的不錯  - 謝謝
- Good job. - Thanks.
你覺得他們會喜歡嗎
Do you think people liked it?
我覺得他們會愛死你的
I think they loved you.
這個主意太棒了
I think it was a great idea.
我太開心了
I am so happy.
謝謝你能來
Thank you for coming.
嘿  老爸
Hey, dad.
嘿
Hey.
聽說了今天是個大日子了  哈
Heard it's a big day, huh?
交流發電機今天要裝進去了
The alternator's going in today, you know.
- 嗯  - 嗯
- Yep. - Yep.
你臉上寫滿了“亞當式憂慮”
Uh-oh,you got that "Adam concerned" look on your face.
你怎么了
What's going on with you?
意大利  老爸
Italy, dad.
意大利
Italy.
你老媽的超級旅行  對吧
Oh, your mom's big trip, huh?
可以理解  我們都在想啊
Yeah,and,understandably,we're all wondering.
你為什么不去呢
Why you're not going.
嗯
Oh, yeah.
你們都在想  那你就是代表咯  是嗎
All of you wondering.You're the delegate,are you?
對  我們都知道你不去
I am,and we all know there's got to be some bigger reason
其中肯定有原因
why you decided not to go.
我不去是因為我不想去
I'm not going because I don't want to go.
好吧 或許這并不是你想不想去的問題
All right, maybe it's not about what you want.
或許你需要考慮一下
Maybe you need to think about
老媽需要什么來做出改變
what mom wants for a change.
你能為她這么做嗎
Can you do that for her?
天吶 我真不敢相信你會說這種話
Oh, my God, I can't believe you're saying that.
- 是嗎  - 等等  等等
- What? - Hold it, hold it, hold it.
幫我一把  行嗎
Give me a hand up, would you?
- 把我拉起來  - 好的
- Pick me up here. - Yep.
好吧 亞當  我來告訴你發生了什么事兒
Okay, Adam, I'll tell you what's going on here.
她想買了這棟房子
She wants to sell the house, you know.
你母親想賣掉我們的房子
Your mother wants to sell our house.
- 是嗎  - 對
- What? - Yeah.
對 對 哦 對了
Yeah, yeah. Oh yeah.
她說得好像我們突然就到了開始晚年生活的時候
She talking like, all of a sudden we're in the third act
我們的生活就該做一些事兒
of our lives, and, like, we're doing some kind
而且自從晚年生活開始之后
of a play or something,and since we're in the third act
我們就得搬去小一點的房子
of our lives, we should be moving into something smaller,
比如說公寓之類的  跟個小盒子似的
like maybe a condo,that's shaped like a box.
好吧
Okay.
然后我們就可以做一些有文化的事兒
And then we can go to all these cultural affairs,
去參觀參觀博物館  而且這樣我們
and we can go see museums, and, by the way,
就穿得跟個準男爵一樣去了
we can get on the Bart to go do that.
好吧
Okay.
這就是她要談的事兒
That's what she's talking about.
那可不是我的生活
Well, that's not my life.
這才是我的生活  這才是我的家
This happens to be my life, and this is our home.
好了  我懂了  明白了  好嗎
Okay, I get it,I get it, okay?
就其價值而言  我不希望你賣掉這所房子
For what it's worth,I don't want you to sell the house.
但我們可以給老媽一點空間
Okay,but maybe we can allow mom a little space to just
去說出她自己的想法  知道嗎
be able to introduce this for conversation, you know?
很多你們這個年紀的人都想朱小點的房子
Plenty of couples your age think about downsizing.
等等  你是不是剛剛說了“像我們這個年紀”
Oh, now wait a minute.Did you say "our age"?
我是說了
I did.
你說“像我們這個年紀”的夫妻是什么意思
What does that mean, couples "our age"?
你知道我在說什么 好嗎
You know what I'm talking about, okay.
她不是從外太空來的
She's not coming from outer space, here.
別人都那么做  還有  聽著
It's, like, people do that, and, look,
你現在可以將房子擱下
maybe you can just table the house for right now,
然后去意大利
and you can just go to Italy.
跟你的妻子一起度假
Have this adventure with your wife,and,you know,
你回來的時候房子也不會消失
this will be here for you when you get back,
到時候你想怎么處理都行  老爸  你可以去的
and you can deal with it,but,dad,you can go away.
多給自己一點時間  多看一些景色
Get a little time, a little perspective.
好了  別說了  我都看了一輩子的景色了
Oh, come on, I've gota lifetime of perspective.
- 我不需要看什么景色   - 天吶 老爸
- I don't need perspective. - God, dad.
我只是讓你想一個男人一樣心胸寬廣一點
I'm just asking you to suck it up and be a man,
去意大利陪你的妻子而已
and go to Italy with your wife.
你想讓我心胸寬廣些什么
What are you telling me to suck it up?
你就跟你老爹這樣說話的嗎
You're talking to your father like that?
讓我來告訴你
Let me tell you something.
我來告訴你為什么我不想去
I will tell you the real reason I'm not going.
- 好吧 說吧  - 行 行
- Okay, tell me. - Okay, okay.
我告訴你為什么
I'll tell you why.
她根本就沒問我去不去
I was not invited.
喂~
Hello.
- 嘿  我是茱莉亞   - 嘿
- Hey, it's Julia. - Hey.
我很抱歉現在才給你回電話
I'm sorry I didn't call you back until now.
我剛剛才看到你留的信息
I actually just found your messages now.
沒關系  你還好嗎
That's cool. How are you?
哦  好得很呢
Oh, fine.
就到處找工作啊
Job hunting,
接孩子放學之前在家里做做家務啥的
doing a few things around the
house before I pick up the kids.
是嗎
Uh Huh.
那你覺得還好嗎
How are you?
真是不太好
Really not good.
別跟我說一切都會好起來的
And don't tell me that everything's gonna be all right.
我才不會這樣說呢  因為我老婆說“根本不會好起來的”
I would never tell you that,"'cause it's not" says my wife.
抱歉  這么說是有點太消極了
Sorry. That was low hanging fruit.
事實上  她在這個家里可樂觀呢
She's actually the optimist around this house.
- 說吧  出什么事了  - 我也說不太清楚
- So what's going on? - I don't know.
我整天就一個人在家閑著
I'm all over the place.
我還對我家孩子大吼大叫
I'm either yelling at my kids,
跟我老公也沒什么交流
not communicating with my husband.
我們就談了那么十分鐘
In the ten minute windows that we have,
就讓我們倆簡直尷尬的要死  跟受罪一樣
generally making everyone miserable including myself.
聽起來比我之前想象的要糟得多
This is sounding way worse than I intended,
這周確實太難熬了
but it's been a rough week.
我這兒也一樣啊  但突然我電話就響了
Yeah, same here, and then my phone rang,
然后感覺一下子就好了許多
and it suddenly got a lot better.
哦~ 哈嘍
Oh. Hello.
好吧  我們速戰速決
Yeah, I'm gonna make this quick,
還有  我不會進你家門的
and I'm not gonna come in.
我沒打算讓你進來
I didn't ask you in.
好吧  我一直在想你說的那些
Yeah, uh, I was thinking about what you said,
關于麥克斯跟什么“最好的朋友”之類的事
about Max, and the whole "best friend" thing.
聽著  什么朋友啊 好朋友什么的  我反正是搞不懂啦
Look,I don't know... friends,best friends, I don't...
給什么都貼上標簽不是我的風格
labels, that's not me.
我挺喜歡他的  麥克斯那小子
I like him. I like Max.
挺聰明挺有天賦的一小家伙
Smart, talented kid, you know,
他就跟我過去一樣  就是個癡迷攝影的笨蛋
and he's a camera nerd, like I used to be.
過去是嗎
Used to be?
你還是挺了解我的
You still got it.
聽著  這小家伙非常渴望
Look, he's eager.
他極其渴望去攝影
God, he's eager, this kid.
我不是說他沒有自己的時間
I'm not saying he doesn't have his moments,
但我在教他這一系列的東西
but I'm showing him the ropes,
這對他來說挺好的
and it's good for him.
對我也有好處
And it's good for me.
所以  我還是會讓他來我這兒
So the kid stays.
- 謝謝  - 嗯
- Thank you. - Yeah.
很好  謝謝
Good, thank you.
順便提一下  我貌似還家里還有
And by the way,there were,like, seven or eight
另外七八張你的照片
other pictures of you I had scattered around.
我已經把它們都扔了   這樣你就不必再
I got rid of them so you won't come up
到我那兒去找我談談了
in conversation anymore.
別說了啦
Shut up.
好吧  你做了什么
All right.What did you do?
你都發好像確實不一樣了誒
You did your hair different?
- 是你頭發不一樣了  - 沒有啊
- Is your hair different? - No.
還是你的牙...你有沒有...
Or your teeth...did you do...
我有沒有做牙嗎
did I do my teeth different?
沒有  還是我原來的牙齒
No, they're just my teeth.
- 你到底想說什么啊  - 我還是走吧
- What are you saying? - I'm trying to get out.
好吧
Oh, okay.
好吧  改日再見
All right. I'll see you later.
你就說聲再見嗎
You just say goodbye.
好了  不許偷看啊  好嗎
Okay. No peeking, all right?
瑞恩  到底是什么呀
Ryan, what is this?
- 我現在老緊張了  - 就等一會兒  不許看
- I'm stressed out. - One sec.Don't look!
- 你在偷看嗎   - 好吧  我沒有
- Are you looking? - Okay, I'm not.
我我沒有偷看
I didn't.
好了  睜開眼睛吧
Okay, open them.
我第一次向你求婚的時候
The first time I asked you,it was impulsive,
太沖動了  就突發奇想而已
and it was spur of the moment,
之后我就一直在想這件事
and since then I've had nothing but time to think about it,
我現在在肯定不過了
and I couldn't be more sure.
自從我遇到你之后  我的人生就發生了重大轉折
My life changed the day that I met you,
我不想再多過一天沒有你的日子
and I don't want to spend another day of it without you.
我愛你
I love you.
我想讓你成為我的妻子
I want you to be my wife.
瑞恩
Ryan.
- 怎么啦   你開什么玩笑呢  - 我們負擔不起這個戒指的
- What?You're kidding me? - That's..we can't afford this.
我們當然負擔得起  我把退伍津貼花在上面了
Yes, of course we could.I spent my combat pay on it.
我想把它花在該花的地方  而這就是
I wanted to spend it on the right thing,and this is it.
這太貴重了
That's... that's too much.
不不不
No, no, no.
我還有獎金
I get extra pay for active duty,
我都把它們存起來了
and I was saving it up.
我想...
I wanted to...
你確定嗎
are you sure?
我從沒有這么確定過
I've never been so sure of anything, ever.
親愛的  我...
Honey,I...
這是正式的  好嗎
it's official, all right?
嘿
Hey.
嘿 你好
Hey, you.
嗯  你不打算要請我進去嗎
Um, you gonna invite me in?
還是我們得再做個這手勢呢
Or should we do another one of these?
- 好吧  - 碰一下
- Oh, all right, yeah. - Pound that?
- 哈哈  - 太棒了
- Ha, ha - great.
我被你給搞迷糊了
I'm confused.
我是說
Honestly, I mean...
我們是朋友  對吧
We're friends, you know.
但我們又不是普通的朋友
We're also more than friends, you know,
你又不想交男朋友
and you don't want a boyfriend,
可是你現在又到這兒來了
but then also, you're here.
對啊
Yes.
我是不是不該再多嘴了
I guess I should just stop talking.
嗯哼
MmHmm.
我不知道你為什么不想讓我送你
I don't know why you won't let me take you.
時間還很充足呢
There's still time, you know.
因為這樣輕松多了
Because this is so much easier,
你得回床上躺著去
and you get to go back to bed.
好吧
Right.
好吧  我想是時候該說再會了
Well, okay, well, I guess it's arrivederci.
或者是再見  還是什么的
Or ciao or whatever.
- 就這兩個行李嗎  - 對
- Just these two? - Yes, that's it.
輕裝旅行
Traveling light.
好了
Okay.
我在檢查一遍我是不是什么都帶了
Let me just check I've got everything.
機票帶了  眼鏡也帶了
Tickets, my glasses.
都齊了
I'm good.
嗯
Yeah.
好吧
Okay.
好了
一路順風  米莉
You be careful, Millie.
哦~  別這樣
Oh, come on.
天吶
Oh, my God.
謝謝觀賞  更多字幕請關注“幕雨字幕組”新浪微博